Finding Aid for the Claude Lee Finney Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- PIERPONT MORGAN LIBRARY: CHARLES WENTWORTH DILKE’S COMMENTS ON RICHARD MONKTON MILNES’ LIFE, LETTERS AND LITERARY REMAINS OF JOHN KEATS
  Title page; preface (ix), x, xi, xii, xiii, xiv, xv, xviii, xix; pp. 4, 5, 8, 9, 20, 21, 24, 25, 28, 29, 30, 31, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 46, 47, 50, 51, 52, 53, 56, 57, 58, 59, 62, 63, 68, 69, 86, 87, 97, 108, 109, 122, 142, 143, 150, 151, 168, 169, 172, 173, 174, 175, 188, 189, 198, 199, 208, 209, 212, 213, 214, 215, 228, 229, 240, 241, 244, 245, 256, 257, 258, 259, 274, 275, 288, (289); Volume II, pp. 10, 11, 18, 19, 28, 29, 38, 39, 40, 41, 42, 43, 46, 47, 50, 51, 53, 60, 61, 70, 71, 76, 77.
HARVARD UNIVERSITY LIBRARY
Wentworth Place Monday morn Severn
Carlisle 5 1818 John Taylor B. Bailey
Hampstead 8 Mar " " Charles Brown
Hampstead 18 Mar 1821 " " " "
Hampstead 24 Jul 1821 " "
Exmouth 21 Sep 1820 John Taylor
Wentworth Place 12 Aug Charles Brown
Louisville 11 May 1832 Charles Dilke George Keats
Hampstead Tues. evening John Taylor " "
5 Aug 1825 Charles Dilke " "
Louisville 10 Apr 1824 " " " "
Rome (copy) 14 Dec 1820 Charles Brown Joseph Severn
" " 15 Jan 1821 My dear Madam
Naples 1 Nov 1820 " "
Louisville 23 Nov 1833 Charles Dilke George Keats
Rome (copy) 11 Jan 1820 Mrs. Brawn Joseph Severn
Keats Richard Woodhouse
- JOHN HAMILTON REYNOLDS’ COPIES OF KEATS’S POEMS FROM COMMONPLACE BOOK BRISTOL LIBRARY (Manuscript poems of John Keats)
  - Ode to Apollo, J. Keats (Folder 25a)
  - To -----, J. Keats, Nov. 11 1817 (Folder 26)
  - Sonnet, J. H. Reynolds, 8 Feb 1818 27a. Answer, J. Keats (Folder 27)
  - Sonnet on the Sea, J. Keats, Aug 1818 (Folder 28)
  - Sonnet -- On sitting down to read "King Lear" once again, J. K., 22 Jan. 1818 (Folder 28a)
  - Sonnet — To the Nile, J. K., Feb. 6, 1818 (Folder 29)
  - To -----, J.K., 4 Feb. 1818 (Folder 29a)
  - Lines on visiting "Staffa," J.K. (Folder 30)
  - When I have fears that I may cease to be, from J. Keats’ letter to J.H.R., 31 Jan 18181 (Folder 31)
  - Hence Burgundy, claret and port, J.K., Feb. 7, 1818 (Folder 31a)
  - The fall of Hyperion. A Dream. Canto 1st, J. Keats. (Folder 33)
  - Stanzas, J.K. (You say you love, but with a voice) (Folder 39)
  - On seeing a lock of Milton’s hair. Ode., J.K., 21 Jan 1818 (Folder 39a)
  - Extracts from an Opera, J. K., 1818 (Folder 40a)
  - Sonnet translated from Ronsard, 1818 (Folder 41a)
    CHARLES WENTWORTH DILKE -- Biographical information
- MARY STRANGE MATHEW’S COMMONPLACE BOOK: THE GARLAND: Consisting of Poetical Extracts both ancient and modern ... 1816
  Poems by KEATS:
  p. 95: Homer (missing from this copy)
  Authors of other poems are identified in Index as: Mathew, Shakespear Homer, Cowper, Rior, Maw, Cunningham, Leffler, Virgil, Campbell, Lane Glover, Thompson, Langhorne, Smollett, Rogers, Southey, Moore, Byron, Scott, Hyles, Waring, Bayley, etc.
- NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY
  - Fragment of Lamia, I, 324-329. (Folder 1)
  - Fragment of Ode on Melancholy, stanza III. (Folder 2)
    UNIVERSITY OE TEXAS -- MANUSCRIPT OF OTHO THE GREAT
- HENRY E. HUNTINGTON LIBRARY
  - Autograph manuscript of sonnet "Before he went to feed with owls and bats." (Folder 1)
  - Autograph manuscript of four stanzas (9, 10, 11, & 12) of Isabella. (Folder 2)
  - Autograph manuscript of poetic epistle to Charles Cowden Clarke. (Folder 3)
  - Autograph manuscript of fragment of Otho (Act IV, scene 2, and Act V). (Folder 4)
Abbey, Richard
Aitken, John
Blunden, Edmund
Bailey, Benjamin
Bosworth, Joseph
Brawne, Fanny
Brown, Charles Armitage
Brown, Lloyd A.
British Museum
Carmichael, Katherine
Clarke, Dr.
Clarke, Charles Cowden
Clarke, James Freeman
Clarke, Mary Cowden
Clough, A. H.
Colim, Professor
Cooper, Sir Astley Paston
Cornelius, Roberta D.
Crump, T. G.
Dilke, Charles Wentworth
Dilke, Fisher
Dilke, Maria
Drury, Michael
Edgcumbe, Fred
Elkins, William M.
Eric, Howard
Fields, James T.
Finney, Claude Lee
Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania
Gray, Mr.
Gregory, John
Harvard College Library, Amy Lowell Collection
Haslam, William
Haverford College, Roberts Collection
Hawilt, Mary
Haydon, B. R.
Hessey, Mr.
Holman, Louis
Holmes, Edward
Houghton, Arthur A.
Hunt, Leigh
Hutchings, J.
Illinois, University of, Library
Iowa, University of, Library
Jeffrey, John
Jenner, Edward
Keats, Miss
Keats, George
Keats, Georgianna
Keats, John
"As doth a Mother wild..."
"As Hermes once todtto his feathers light..."
"A Dream, after Reading Dante’s Episode of Paulo and Francesca
"The Eve of Saint Agnes"
"The Eve of Saint Mark"
"Ever let the fancy roam"
"Extracts from an Opera"
"The Fall of Hyperion"
"Fragment" ("Welcome, joy...")
"Fragment" ("Where’s the Poet?...)
"Hadst thou lived in days of old..."
"Hyperion"
"I Stood Tiptoe"
"Isabella or The Pot of Basil"
"Lines on Seeing a Lock of Milton’s Hair"
"Lines on the Mermaid Tavern"
"Lines written in the Highlands..."
"Lines written in the Scotch Highlands"
"Lines on Visiting Staffa"
"Lines written upon reading a sonnet by J. H. Reynolds"
"Ode" ("Souls of poets..."
"Ode on a Grecian Urn"
"Ode on Melancholy"
"Ode to Apollo"
"Ode to the Nightingale"
"Old Meg"
"On First Looking into Chapman’s Homer"
"On Seeing the Elgin Marbles"
"On Sitting Down to Read King Lear Once Again" "Otho"
"The Poetry of Earth is never dead"
"Sleep and Poetry"
"Song" ("Hnnce Burgundy...")
"Song" ("Hush, hush...")
"Song" ("In drear-nighted December...")
"Sonnet" ("After dark vapors...")
"Sonnet" ("As from the darkening gloom...")
"Sonnet" ("High-mindedness...")
"Sonnet" ("Life’s sea...")
"Sonnet" ("Oh, how I love...")
"Sonnet ("If by dull rhymes...")
"Sonnet" ("When I have fears...")
"Sonnet on a Dream"
"Sonnet on Fame"
"Sonnet on Mrs. Reynolds’s cat"
"Sonnet on the Grasshopper and the Cricket" "Sonnet on the Sea"
"Sonnet to a young lady who sent me a laurel crown"
"Sonnet to Homer"
"Sonnet to Sk Sleep"
"Sonnet to the Nile"
"Sonnet translated from Ronsard"
"Stanzas"
"To Autumn"
"To Haydon"
"To John Reynolds in answer to his sonnets on Robin Hood"
"To Kosciusko"
"To Solitude"
"Wine, Women and Snuff"
"Written on a blank space at the end of Chaucer’s tale of ’The Floure and the Lefe’"
Keats, Rosa Llanos
Kirkaan, Mr.
Landon, W. S. (?)
Landrum, Grace Warren
Leffler, Frederick Leigh, Sarah
Leigh, Thomazine (Tamsine)
"Lines 4n Seeing a Portrait of Keats"
Llanos, Frances Keats de
Locker, Frederick
Lowell, Amy
Maine Historical Collection
Markwood, Robert (?)
Massachusetts Historical Society
Mathew, Caroline
Mathew, George Felton
Mathew, Selina
Milnes, Richard Monkton
Moxen, Edward
Neville, Henry
New York Public Library, Owen D. Young Collection Newton, A. Edward Nicholson, Cregoe D. P. Norton, Mrs.
Novello, Mr. No vello, Mary
"One Daisy and Two Violets"
Oilier, Mr.
Patmore, Doventry
Payne, John Howard
Pierpont Morgan Library
Pershing, James H.
Pratt, Dallas
Prentice, G. D.
Proslet, A. B.
Reseigh, T.
Reynolds, Jane
Reynolds, Hohn Hamilton
Richardson, Benjamin Ward
Rice, James
Rosenbach, A. S. W.
Schulz, Herbert C.
Bcottish National Portsait Galle
Severn, Emma Severn, Joseph Shelley, P. B. Smith, Horace Sotheby
South Kensington Museum, Dyce and Forster Collection
Speed, John Gilmer
Spencer, Walter T.
Stephens, Henry
Stern, Madeleine B.
Storr, Severn
Taylor, James
Taylor, John
Thomas, Ralph
Thorpe, Clarence D.
Tighe, Mary
Tracy, Rev. Thomas
Trinity College Library, Cambridge
Venable, Francis Edward
Ward, Anna H. B.
Weller, Earle Vonard
Woodhouse, George
Woodhouse, Richard
Wordsworth, William
Wylie, Henry R.
Wylie, Mrs.
Young, Owen D.
Zweig Estate
LETTERS RECEIVED AFTER PUBLICATION OF "LIFE & LETTERS."
164r Bayswater 7 Aug. 1848 R. M. Milnes C. Cowden Clarke
168r 8 Aug. 1848 " " " T. Reseigh
169r 9 Aug. 1848 " " George Woodhouse
171r Newport 10 Aug. 1848 " " John Hamilton Reynolds
175r Kensington 14 Aug. 1848 " " George Felton Mathew
183r Somerset House 15 Aug. 1848 " " " "
185r 15 Aug. " " Jeffrey
189r " " C. W. Dilkes
193r North Brixton 29 Aug. 1848 " " Edward Holmes
194r Edinburgh 22 Aug. 1848 " " Robert Markwood (?)
196r Bath 29 Aug. " " W. S. Landon (?)
200r Bloomsbury 21 Aug. 1848 " " Joseph Bosworth
201r " " Emma Severn
203r Beaconsfield 18 Dec. 1848 " " Francis Edward Venable
206r Colombo, Ceylon 15 Oct. 1848 " " J. B. Bailey
2l4r Ceylon 7 May 1949 " " " "
282r Colombo 11 May 1849 " " " "
- THE LITERARY DIARY: OR, IMPROVED COMMON-PLACE-BOOK (etc.) — RICHARD WOODHOUSE, TEMPLE, NOV. 1818
  - "As doth a Mother wild ...,", Feb. 1818 (Folder 11)
  - "To J.H.R. -- In answer to his Robin Hood sonnets,", 3 Feb. 1819 (Folder 12)
  - "Sonnets on Robin Hood," Yellow Dwarf, 21 Feb. 1818 (Folder 15)
  - "Lines on the Mermaid Tavern" (Folder 16)
  - "Sonnet written by J. H. Reynolds in a collection of M.S. poetry, 8 Feb. 1818 (Folder 17)
  - "Hadst thou lived in days of old,", 14 Feb. 1816 (Folder 18)
  - "To ----," J.K., abt. 11 Nov. 1817 from K’s M.S. (Folder 20)
  - "Sonnet," J.K., 1816 ("Oh, how I love ...") (Folder 21)
  - "Sonnet," J.K., 1816 ("As from the darkening gloom ...") (Folder 22)
  - "Sonnet," J. Keats, Jan. 31, 1817 ("After dark vapors ...") (Folder 23)
  - "Sonnet written on a blank space at the end of Chaucer’s tale ’The flowre or the lefe," J.K., Feb. 7, 1817 (Folder 24)
  - "Sonnet to Keats. On reading his sonnet written in Chaucer," J. H. Reynolds, 27 Feb. 1817 (Folder 25)
  - "Sonnet — To a young lady who sent me a laurel crown," J. Keats (Folder 26)
  - "Sonnet -- On Mrs. Reynolds’s cat," J. Keats, 16 Jan. 1818 (Folder 27)
  - "On sitting down to read King Lear once again," J. Keats (Folder 28)
  - "Time’s sea has been five years ...," J. Keats, 4 Feb. 1818 (Folder 29)
  - "Lines written upon reading a sonnet by J.H. Reynolds, which will be found p. 17." (Folder 30)
  - "To the Nile," Feb. 6, 1818, J.K. (Folder 31)
  - "Sonnet -- On the Sea," J.K., Champion, 17 Aug 1817 (Folder 32)
  - "Lines Rhymed in a letter received (by J.H.R.) from Oxford, J.K., abt. Midsr 1818 (Folder 33)
  - "Song," J. Keats, abt. Oct. or Dec. 1818 ("In drear-nighted December") 36. "Fragment of an Ode to Apollo," J.Keats. (Folder 34)
  - "Hyperion. Book 1st." (Folder 39)
  - "Book 2nd." (Folder 63)
  - "Book 3rd." (Folder 89)
  - "Saint Agnes’ Eve." (Folder 108)
  - "Lines on visiting Staffa,", 26 Mar. 1819 (Folder 138)
  - "When I have fears that I may cease to be,", Feb. 1818 (Folder 144)
  - "Sonnet. To Homer," 1818; "La belle Dame sans Mercy — A Ballad,", 1819 (Folder 146)
  - "Fragment," 1818 ("Welcome joy and welcome sorrow") (Folder 150)
  - "Lines on the Mermaid Tavern (Folder 154)
  - "As Hermes once took to his feathers light." (Folder 156)
  - "Sonnet. To Sleep."(Irregular), 1819; "D°. On the Sonnet." (Irregular) (Folder 158)
  - "Sonnet. On Fame," 1819; "Lines on seeing a lock of Milton’s hair," Jan. 7, 1818. 164. "Ode to the Nightingale,", May 1819 (Folder 160)
  - "Isabella or The Pot of Basil," J.K., written at Teignmouth in the spring of 1818 at the suggestion of J.H.R. (Folder 172)
UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS LIBRARY: LETTERS RECEIVED DURING PREPARATION OF "LIFE, LETTERS & LITERARY REMAINS"
1r Louisville 13 May 1845 R. M. Milnes John Jeffrey
3r " 26 July 1845 " " " " " "
7r " 8 Sep. 1845 " " " " " "
9r 13 Feb. 1845 " " " John Taylor
13r Boston 31 Oct. 1845 " " " James Freeman Clarke
15r 22 Dec. 1846 " " " J. H. Reynolds
20r 30 Dec. " " " " " "
24r Newport 22 June " " " " " "
27r 17 Apr. 1848 " " " " " "
31r 8 May 1847 " " " William Haslam
34r London 6 Oct. " " " Joseph Severn
40r " 13 July " " " " " "
54r " 5 May " " " " " "
58r Bayswater 21 Dec. 1846 " " " Charles Cowden Clarke
59r C. C. Clarke Edward Holmes
60r 9 Dec. 1846 R. M. Milnes " " "
64r Bayswater 17 Mar. 1846 " " " Charles Cowden Clarke
78r " " " " " " " " "
84r Stratford 26 Mar. 1846 " " " " " "
86r Bayswater 20 Dec. 1846 " " " " " "
90r 3 Sep. " " " C. W. Dilke
94r 2 June " " " " " "
97r 29 Dec. " " " " " "
103r Kensington 22 Dec. " " " Leigh Hunt
107r " 21 Jan. " " " " " "
111r " 7 May " " " " " "
113r London 20 May 1846 " " " Haydon
115r 6 Jan. 1847 " " " Frederick Leffler
116r Kensington 12 Jan. 1846 " " " George Felton Mathew
118r " 3 Feb. 1847 " " " " " "
124r 11 Feb. 1847 " " " " " "
130r G. F. Mathew Henry Stephens
141r Bideford 9 Feb. 1847 R. M. Milnes Caroline Mathew
(85) Trieste 30 Jan. 1847 " " " A. H. Clough
145r Paris 2 July 1847 " " " John Howard Payne
150r " " G. D. Prentice " " "
152r Clapton 29 May R. M. Milnes Mary Hawilt
154r Eshen 22 May 1847 Mary Hawilt M. Neville
156r St. Johns Wood 2 June 1847 R. M. Milnes George Woodhouse
159r 14 May 1846 " " " A. B. Proslet
161r Camden Town 24 Mar. " " " Coventry Patmore
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Keats letter to Severn, undated (June 6, 1818) — possessed by Howard Eric, New York City (Folder 1)
  - Dedication Page to Poems, presented to G. F. Mathew — possessed by Howard Eric, New York City (Folder 2)
  - "Sleep and Poetry" mss. (157-73, 181-95), Dallas Pratt, 139 E. 40 St., New York City (Folder 3)
  - "Sleep and Poetry" ms., possessed by William M. Elkins (Folder 4)